Sure you're not pushing yourself too hard?
你會不會太拼了？
EPISODE 12: KAFKA HIBINO
（第12集：日比野卡夫卡）
What are you thinking, anyway?
你在想什麼啊？
You're not worried about the old dude?
你就不擔心大叔嗎？
You went and agreed to go to another unit.
而且還答應轉調到其他部隊
I want to get stronger.
因為我想變強
You can do that here, right?
在這裡也做得到吧
That's how we've done it so far!
我們不就是在這裡變強的嗎？
Yeah.
的確
I'm sure I could get stronger if I stayed, too.
我知道留在這裡也能變強
But...
可是
I want to get stronger as quickly as possible.
我想要更快一點變強
So that next time I can protect him, instead of him having to protect me.
我不想總是受到前輩的保護 下次要換我來保護他了
Next time? You really think the old dude's coming back?
下次？你覺得大叔還回得來嗎？
I've decided to believe.
我相信他
And when he comes back, I don't want to rue my own weakness.
到時候，我不想再因為自己的軟弱而後悔
Well, me too...!
我又何嘗不是啊
Fine, damn it! I'll train too!
我也要好好鍛鍊，可惡
You're the one guy I refuse to lose to!
我才不會輸給你這傢伙
What are you two arguing about?
你們怎麼這麼吵鬧啊？
Platoon leaders...
前輩你們…
Today's the day they decide what they're doing with Hibino.
今天會決定日比野的處分吧
It's hard to stay focused, thinking about that.
一想到這件事就覺得靜不下心
Same for you guys, right?
你們也一樣吧？
It'll be fine!
沒問題的
We all wrote that letter asking for clemency together!
大家都幫忙寫請願書了
And Captain Ashiro was summoned to HQ, too.
亞白隊長也被叫去總部基地了
The captain was?
隊長被叫去了？
Yes.
是的
I'm sure they called her because they have good news.
一定是有好消息才會叫她過去
Mina Ashiro, reporting as ordered.
亞白米娜，奉命前來報到
Director General Shinomiya is currently examining Kaiju No. 8.
四之宮長官正在對怪獸8號進行評估
Please remain there until he's finished.
評估結束前，請在此等候
Roger.
瞭解
You are only here as an observer.
你的身分是觀察員
A seat has not been prepared for you.
所以沒有準備你的座位
No! You're human, right?
住手，你是人類吧？
Kafka Hibino!
日比野卡夫卡！
He's fast.
動作真迅速
But he's just an animal.
但這終究只是
He's not thinking about the opening he leaves after his attack.
怪獸會使出的攻擊 並沒有考慮到出招後的破綻
An attack that destroys his own body, knowing he can regenerate?
以再生為前提的自我破壞攻擊？
If I try to use human common sense in this fight, I'm going to regret it.
如果我用人類的常識來思考 就會被乘虛而入吧
Stop it!
住手！
Daddy!
爸爸！
Without No. 2's shield, that would've killed me instantly.
要是沒有2號的防護盾 我大概早已一命嗚呼了吧
Squadron-Style Combat Technique Number Two:
隊式格鬥術2式
Force Blast!
爆破！
That attack expands its striking range by using a sonic boom.
運用音爆擴大打擊範圍
A method No. 2 put to good use.
這是2號常用的攻擊方法
The core's gone?
核心不見了？
He used his body as a decoy and regenerated from his core?
他以自己的肉體為誘餌，從核心再生？
Fighting like this is too much!
這種戰鬥方式太亂來了
I'm not gonna survive this!
我的身體會撐不住啊
Impossible! That shelter's as strong as we could make it!
怎麼可能？這可是最堅固的收容所啊
We just lost the second layer!
只是第二層遭到破壞了而已
In theory, it should survive an attack from a Fortitude 10.0!
照理來說，這裡可以承受 怪獸規模10.0的強度
We can expect to take some damage.
遭受一點損害在所難免
After all, we have two identified Kaiju,
畢竟這是兩隻跨越時空的識別怪獸
No. 2 and No. 8, battling each other across time.
2號和8號之間的激烈對戰
Incredible...
好厲害
He's facing an identified Kaiju all on his own!
單憑一己之力就能與識別怪獸勢均力敵
It's strange, though.
但是，好奇怪啊
If he was going to kill him, he should've done so
如果想殺掉牠，趁著還是人類形態時
with his first attack while he was still in human form.
第一擊就解決牠就好了
Instead, it looks like Isao
但是，功他卻…
is deliberately pushing No. 8 to test him.
好像是刻意在逼迫8號，測試他的能耐
I can't imagine why.
真不曉得他有何意圖
Is Daddy giving Kafka Hibino a chance to survive?!
爸爸他該不會是想給 日比野卡夫卡活命的機會？
I came to the Defense Force to save lives.
我是為了救人而加入防衛隊
Instead, Kafka Hibino saved mine.
結果我卻被日比野卡夫卡拯救了
But he...
但是，那傢伙…
Your standard for judging someone
評斷一個人的標準
shouldn't be their background, or what they say.
不應該是看對方的出身或發言
The way I see it, people ought to be judged by their actions.
而是該根據對方的所作所為來判斷 我是這麼認為的
Yeah, you're right.
你說得沒錯
FATHER
（父親）
The only fact that matters is what you do, huh?
所作所為才是真理，是嗎？
No!
不妙
No. 8's fortitude is starting to surpass Isao's estimations.
8號的強度開始超出功的預料了
Crap! I have to stop this thing!
糟糕，我得阻止這傢伙
Damn it all! Stop!
可惡，住手啊！
I'm going to end up killing him!
再這樣下去，長官會被我殺死
Hell no!
開什麼玩笑啊
I'm not killing Kikoru's dad right in front of her!
我怎麼能在琪歌露面前殺死她爸
...if I find out that you're a Kaiju that's going to harm mankind,
要是我發現你是會危害人類的怪獸
I'll kill you.
我就會殺了你
I'll...
我…
I'll... have to...
我要把那個傢伙…
But I still want to believe in him!
即使如此，我還是想相信他
Don't give in to some Kaiju, Kafka, you idiot!
你怎麼能輸給那種怪獸？白痴卡夫卡！
I... I...!
我…
WE REGRET TO INFORM YOU THAT...
（很遺憾通知您…）
This is how it always goes for me.
我每次都這樣
I always screw up at the most important moment.
總是在緊要關頭失敗
Damn it...
可惡
I had hope, but I suppose all is lost.
虧我還有所期待，看來到此為止了嗎？
I'll always...
我會…
I'll always be waiting.
一直等你的
I...
我…
I... I'm not Kaiju No. 8.
我不是怪獸8號
I'm Kafka Hibino.
我是日比野卡夫卡
Put your weapon away,
把武器收起來
Narumi.
鳴海
You kept refusing to signal for backup.
您都不發出支援的暗號
Don't be stupid.
說什麼蠢話
I'll admit he was more than I expected, though.
但我承認他的確超乎了我的預料
Medics, take No. 8 in immediately.
醫療小組，立即收治8號
Its core may be damaged.
牠的核心可能受損了
So, what will you do with him?
所以，您打算如何處置這傢伙？
Director General Shinomiya has finished his examination.
四之宮長官的評估已經結束
Lastly, we want to hear what you think as his commanding officer,
最後，我們想聽聽現場負責人對他的看法
Captain Mina Ashiro.
亞白米娜隊長
Of course.
是
You've seen Kafka Hibino up close since the day he joined.
你從入隊測驗時就看著日比野卡夫卡
Our reports say you know him from before that, as well.
調查報告顯示，你們兩個是舊識
Yes.
是的
But from the trials to now, I haven't given him any special treatment.
但是，從入隊測驗開始 我就從未提供他任何特別待遇
Our records show that she failed Kafka Hibino during the exam.
根據紀錄顯示，她淘汰了日比野卡夫卡
It was Vice-Captain Hoshina's suggestion that he be selected as a backup.
讓他成為候補隊員是保科副隊長的提議
To be clear, we've almost entirely reached our conclusion.
先跟你說，基本上結論已經幾乎定案了
We simply need your report for the paperwork.
你的報告內容只不過是形式上的程序
Which means your testimony will have no influence on Kaiju No. 8's fate.
換句話說，你的發言 不會影響對於怪獸8號的處置
We don't want you to feel responsible for what happens here.
我們並不希望讓你 對於這次的處分結果感到自責
Understood.
是
Speak.
說吧
I'll leave it to the specialists to decide
日比野卡夫卡是人類還是怪獸
whether Kafka Hibino is a human or a Kaiju.
這只能交由專家來判定
Instead, I'll tell you what I know of him as a Defense Force officer.
因此，我想告訴各位 日比野卡夫卡身為隊員的表現
During the Sagamihara Neutralization Operation,
日比野卡夫卡隊員在相模原討伐作戰中
Kafka Hibino contributed to his unit by discovering Yoju reproductive organs.
發現了餘獸的增殖器官，對隊上有所貢獻
He has continued to be a hard worker who saved his comrades' lives many times.
之後他也表現勤奮，數度拯救了隊友
Especially notable was the battle with No. 10,
尤其是在與10號的戰鬥中
where he saved the Third Division from being wiped out by destroying a Yoju bomb.
他破壞了餘獸炸彈 讓第3部隊免於遭到全滅的危機
And so what?
那又如何？
That was only possible because he used his Kaiju power.
他的功勞都是因為使用了怪獸的力量吧
The fact that a rookie officer was capable of all that is proof he's a Kaiju!
日比野卡夫卡只是個新進隊員 這些表現正好證明了他是一隻怪獸
Yes, that's correct.
是，您說得沒錯
His unleashed combat power at the time he joined was 0%.
加入防衛隊時，他的解放戰力是0%
He only passed the exam as a backup.
入隊測驗成績也是低空飛過的候補名額
He'd failed the Defense Force exam twelve times straight prior to that.
至今應考過的防衛隊測驗 他還連續12次落榜
Age-wise, he's also the oldest of any of our recruits.
在年齡方面，他也是新進隊員裡最年長的
So he must've used his Kaiju power to cheat!
所以，這就代表他使用怪獸的力量作弊啊
But he didn't give up.
但是，他並沒有放棄
No matter how many times he failed,
就算落榜了好幾次
even though his combat power was zero...
就算解放戰力是零
Even though his body had turned into a Kaiju...
然後，就算身體變成了怪獸
He never stopped trying to save people.
他也從未放棄拯救他人
Out of all the people I know, Kafka Hibino
就我所知，日比野卡夫卡
hates giving up, cares for others more than anyone,
比誰都還有毅力，也甘願為他人犧牲奉獻
and...
而且…
Miiko!
咪可
And he has more humanity than anyone.
而且，他比誰都更像個人類
What is the deciding factor as to whether
關於日比野卡夫卡是不是值得信賴的隊員
Kafka Hibino should be trusted as an officer?
要以什麼作為判斷基準？
I believe it's his heart.
我相信要以他的內心來判斷
We're not asking your personal opinion!
我們不是在詢問你的感想
Stop trying to cover for your subordinate.
別再試圖包庇下屬了
We can't trust something as vague and ill-defined as his "heart"!
誰能相信內心這種不確切的東西啊？
Thank you, Captain Ashiro.
辛苦了，亞白隊長
Return to your post.
你可以回去了
We've heard what his commanding officer felt.
我們也聽取了現場負責人的意見
Nobody will accuse us of a hasty decision now.
這樣就不會有人指控我們倉促決定了吧
We're ready to dispose of him now.
處置程序已經準備就緒了
Your decision, Director General.
長官，請您作出決定吧
No. 8 will...
8號…
I hated myself for not being able to do anything.
好不甘心，自己這麼無能為力
I told myself I'd make the Kaiju pay for making her cry like that.
我絕不會原諒害米娜哭得這麼傷心的怪獸
So I'd decided that if I was gonna become a Kaiju in both body and mind,
所以，如果我的身心都會變成怪獸
I'd rather die as a human.
那我寧可身為人類死去
I'm... alive?
我還活著？
You're awake?
你醒了啊
D-Director General Shinomiya!
四之宮長官
Calm down.
別緊張
I'm not here to hurt you.
我不會傷害你
I'm so glad...
太好了…
If anything happened to you,
要是長官您有個什麼萬一
I could never face Kikoru.
我就沒臉見琪歌露了
If I'm still alive, does that mean you accept that I'm human?
既然我還活著，就表示您認同我是人類
That I'm a member of the Defense Force?
也認同我是防衛隊員了嗎？
If what was inside your chest was the frail heart of a human,
如果在你胸口的是人類脆弱的心臟
you would've died back there.
你恐怕早已命喪黃泉
I'll tell you what the council decided.
讓我告訴你會議的結論
You're a Kaiju.
你是一隻怪獸
But we'll decide later if you're a threat.
但至於你是不是敵人，這點還有待觀察
At the moment, most people are opposed to letting you live.
現階段，大部分的人都反對留你一命
Kaiju No. 8 will fight for us. He will not be converted into weaponry.
怪獸8號將暫且作為戰力，不製成兵器
I object!
我反對
We can't use a living Kaiju in combat!
怎麼可以運用活體怪獸？
It's dangerous!
太危險了
There's no precedent!
這毫無前例可言
I'm not Kaiju No. 8.
我不是怪獸8號
I'm Kafka Hibino.
我是日比野卡夫卡
I've decided that he can be controlled.
我判斷他是可以受到控制的
It's a fact that he's been doing missions with the Third Division for months.
實際上，他和第3部隊 已經一同執行任務好幾個月了
It's not clear if a weapon made from him would be able to produce that much power.
我們也無法確定製成兵器後 是否仍能保持那麼強大的力量
With as many Daikaiju as we're seeing,
目前大怪獸頻繁出現
we need to use our forces in the most optimal way possible.
我們必須最有效地運用戰力
But there's no precedent for this.
但是，沒有這種前例啊
Precedent?
前例？
Precedents are meaningless in the face of this country's defense.
跟防衛國家比起來，那根本微不足道
Surely none of you have forgotten
各位一定沒有忘記吧
the series of disasters involving No. 6 ten years ago.
十年前，以6號為中心的群發性災害
Over two hundred officers and three captains lost their lives.
造成兩百多名隊員和三名隊長殉職
Including your wife.
你的妻子也是其中一人
If a swarm of Kaiju emerges with numbers that far exceed our estimates,
萬一接連出現遠遠超出預期數量的怪獸
this nation could easily be destroyed.
這個國家可能就會輕易滅亡
But if we can utilize his incredible power,
要是能運用那傢伙驚人的力量
we might stand a sliver of a chance.
也許能為我們帶來一線曙光
Even so,
就算如此
we stand opposed.
我們仍持反對意見
Kafka Hibino.
日比野卡夫卡
He used my name?
他叫了我的名字
Prove your worth if you want to survive.
如果你想活下去，就得證明自己有所用處
So they're just leaving me alive so I can be used as a weapon?
所以，他們讓我活命 只是為了把我當成兵器嗎？
I still think of myself as a Defense Force officer.
我到現在還是認為自己是防衛隊員
I'll make you accept me as one too!
我一定會讓你認同我是防衛隊員
KAFKA HIBINO: DISPOSAL DEFERRED
（日比野卡夫卡，處分暫緩）
But... I can't be entirely happy.
不過，我不能只顧著高興
Now I need to get stronger...
接下來，我也必須變得更強大
Or I won't be able to stop him if I need to.
不然，我無法在緊要關頭阻止那傢伙
Is this...
這是…
Did the JGSDF do this?
是自衛隊幫的忙嗎？
No, they didn't.
不對
Then this is...
那這是…
A victory Kafka Hibino won for himself!
日比野卡夫卡自己贏得的勝利！
-H—— -Hooray!
-太… -太好了！
You did it, Old Dude!
太好了，大叔！
God was watching out for you, I guess!
正所謂人在做，天在看啊
I'm so glad, Hibino-san!
日比野，真是太好了
It's gonna get noisy around here again.
這下又會變得很熱鬧了
Hey, Reno, it says the old dude's saved!
雷諾，大叔得救了
I knew.
我早就知道了
I told you, right? I was sure he was coming back.
我說過了吧？前輩一定會回來的
When you get back, I'll be way stronger than I am now, Senpai!
我會變得比現在更強 然後等你回來，前輩
I'm glad it worked out for Hibino-san.
日比野的事情，真是太好了呢
The hard part's just beginning, though.
不過，接下來才是挑戰的開始
If people outside the Force knew we had a Kaiju...
要是被外界知道防衛隊裡有怪獸…
Well, it's a secret, right?
這件事會是最高機密吧？
They'll find out someday.
紙終究是包不住火的
I'm sure the brass knows that too.
我相信上頭也有所覺悟了
Then...
那…
Kafka Hibino needs to prove he's useful enough that nobody can refuse his help.
日比野卡夫卡必須展現 能讓所有人心服口服的成果
Things are gonna get even harder from now on.
今後將會變得更加辛苦呢
Hey, we're not done talking.
喂，我話還沒說完
Wake up.
給我醒醒
Wait for me, Mina...
你等著吧，米娜
MONSTER SWEEPER INC.
（Monster Sweeper）
Huh? You lost?
什麼？你輸了嗎？
Game duration of seven minutes? That's fast!
對戰時間才七分鐘，太快了吧
Nothing I could do!
我也沒辦法啊
This "Number 9" guy started playing last week,
這個叫做9號的傢伙，上個禮拜才出現
and all of a sudden he's top of the pile!
結果他一下子就名列前茅
OVERALL RANKING NUMBER 9
（綜合排名，9號）
That should do it.
就這樣啊
I've figured out mankind's intellectual level.
我大概瞭解人類的智慧程度了
On an individual basis, it's nothing special.
以個體來看，沒什麼大不了的
So their weapon is the ability to accumulate knowledge
跨越世代累積智慧
across generations, then.
就是人類的武器嗎？
What about on your end?
你那邊如何？
I've more or less figured out the layout of the base.
我大致掌握了基地的構造
Now we can move our plan to the next phase.
我們可以開始進入下一個作戰階段了
Yes, goodbye.
是啊，那麼…
Time to bring the Kaiju power that fell into human hands
落入人類手中的怪獸力量
back to our side.
就讓我們奪回來吧